Nepal Church History Project Archives
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Addendum, Series XI
  - H - Book and Pamphlet Collection
    - H 06 02 01 and H 07 02 01 (26 titles), 1990s (Box 64, Folder 3)
      Titles: In Grateful and Joyful Commemoration of the 225th Anniversary of the First Catholic Church in Kathmandu (1985); On the Persian Farmans Granted to the Jesuits by the Moghul Emperors by Felix (1912); An Account of the Kingdom of Nepal by Giuseppe and John Shore (1790); Maryknoll: Nepal (1989); Tibet-Hindustan Mission by A. J. Osta (1959); Early Christian Missions in the HImalayas by Dipak Raj Pant (1992); Pray for the Peoples of Nepal (n.d.); A Brief Survey on Agencies from Outside, the Church in Nepal, the Relationship Between the Two and Suggestions for Future Partnership by Jacob George (1996); Status of Christianity Country Profile: Nepal by Roger Hedlund (1980); Conclusions on the Ministry to Nepal (n.d.); Operation World 1992 by Patrick Johnstone (1991); Draft: Jubilee Campaign Statement to the United Nations Human Rights Commission (1990); The MIssion and the Church in Nepal (1977); Church and Mission Relationship in Nepal - Forty Years Ahead by Ramesh Khatry (1996); Hope for Nepal by Ramesh Khatry (1996); Partnership in Mission, a Dream Yet to Come True! by Ramesh Khatry (1996); Worship and Empowering by Ramesh Khatry (1996); The Mixed Record in South-East ASia and the Fringign Islands by KS Latourette (1962); 6 issues of Light of LIfe (November 1972, December 1972, January 1973, February 1973, April 1973, July 1973); 2 copies of Early Church History in Nepal by Peter McDowell (n.d.); The Christian Presence in Nepal Before 1951 by Jan Minderhoud (1990)
    - H 07 01 01 Ramghat Church, Pokhara, Nepal, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - H 07 01/02 Church Growth, 2003 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Church Growth, Helath, Dynamics, and Strategies, a course at the Australian College of Theology by John Barclay. The supervisor is Bruce Dipple and the subject is "A description and analysis of the growth of the Church in Nepal with reference to relevant Church Growth writings." Also included are some emails between Cynthia Hale, Jonathan Bonk, and Betty Young about Church Growth and an article about Church Growth in Nepal.
    - H 07 02 01 (23 titles), 1971-1986 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      These materials also have numbers in the Himalayan Collection, Series M.
      Titles: Concise Dictionary of the Christian World Mission excerpt by S. Neill, G. Anderson, and J. Goodwin (1971); Religious Liberty in Nepal by Simon Pandey (1996); Reflections of a Missionary in the Himalayas by Cindy Perry (1995); Church and Mission in Nepal: the Development of a Unique Relationship by Cindy Perry (1990); Tribute to a Pioneer: Pastor David Mukhia: A man after God's own heart by Cindy Perry (1991); Bodhartha (n.d.); 2 copies of "Bhai-Tika" and "Tij Braka": A Case Study in the Contextualization of Two Nepali Festivals by Cindy Perry (1990); The Church Where There Is No Church by Cindy L. Perry (1990); Nepal Conversation by Donald McGavran, Cindy Perry, and Henrietta Watson (1989); The Growth of the Church in Nepal with reference to A Hindu Perspective, Inter Faith Dialogue, Aid and Development Issues and Prisons by Jim Robertson (1993); Gospel and Culture by K. B. Rokaya (1996); What If All Nepalis Became Christians? by R. B. Rokaya (1996); Towards a Truelly Nepali Church: Contextualization of the Gospel by K. B. Rokaya (n.d.); Evangelism and Social Concern by K. B. Rokaya (n.d.); Affidavit (n.d.); The Gospel Comes to the Hindu Kingdom by Saubhagya Shah (1993); Peoplesfile Index by Allan Starling (1986); Nepal: Location of Languages A Prayer Guide (1985); Ethnologue Languages of the World by Barbara F. Grimes, Richard S. Pittman, and Joseph E. Grimes (1988); Christian Suffering in Asia: Chapter 13: The Church in Nepal by Nicanor Tamang (1989); That the World May Know: Closed Doors by F. A. Tatford (1983); Mission Handbook - North American Protestant Ministries Overseas excerpt by Samuel Wilson (1980)
    - H Miscellaneous Christian Articles - 1, ca.1990-2005 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Titles including, but not limited to... Conversion to Christianity: A Case Study of Lalitpur Sub-Metropolitan City, a dissertation by Ram Kumar Budhathoki (2003); Early Church History in Nepal by Peter McDowell (n.d.); Voice of Bhakti Text and Context in Dialogue magazine (May 2005); The Church at the Top of the World: Nepal's Christians see unprecedented growth in this Hindu kingdom by Anil Stephen (2000); New Evangelical Movements and Conflict in South Asia: Sri Lanka and Nepal in Perspective by Sasanka Perera (1998); Singing the Song of the Lord by Tirtha Thapa (1993)
    - H Miscellaneous Christian Articles - 2 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Titles including, but not limited to... Book in Nepalese; Souvenir: Church History Association of India 8th Triennial Conference 29-31 October 1991 at Christian REtreat and Study Centre, Rajpur Dehradun, Hosted by North India Branch, C.H.A.I. (1991); Other assorted materials relating to the Conference mentioned in the Souvenir, including a photograph.
  - Unclassified Material - Christian Related
    - CEEFI, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      1 booklet in a foreign language - probably Nepali. Also, the file contains a letter written by the CEEFI Secretary Diraisingh James (1991).
    - Delhi Bible Institute, ca.1980s (Box 65, Folder 7)
      Titles: Bible Correspondence Course "Foundations of Faith" translated by Pradeep Pradhan into what looks like Nepalese (n.d.); Foundations of Faith (What The Bible Says): A Discipleship Course for Home Study by Delhi Bible Institute (1984); Nepali translation of DBI follow-up booklet "Everybody Should Know" translated by Pradeep Pradhan (n.d.); 2 copies - Everybody Should Know The Bible and its Message: An Introduction to the study of the Bible by Delhi Bible Institute (n.d.)
    - TAFTEE Materials, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      TAFTEE is The Association for Theological Education by Extension. These materials contain three copies of the Diploma Course - Life of Christ. All three are bound slightly differently and some are longer than others. Also, the file contains some correspondence.
    - Miscellaneous Material in English, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 9)
      Titles: Bibligoraphy of Christianity in Nepal and the HImalayas (with separate sections on Bhutan, Sikkim, the Nepali Bible and Hymn Books and Archival Sources) by Cindy Perry (n.d.)
    - Miscellaneous Material in Nepali, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri -1, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      This folder contains the book "The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri" by Norma Kehrberg (2000) and the news release that announced its publication.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 2, 1990s (Box 66, Folder 2)
      Interview Reports for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 3, 1990s (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Data gathered from statistics analysis for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 4, 1990s (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 5 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      Group 1A Raw Data for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 6 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 7 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Group IB Raw Data for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 8 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 9 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Group 2 Raw Data for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 10 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 11 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      Group 3 Raw Data for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 12 (Box 68, Folder 2, 2)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 13 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Group 4 Raw Data for the book.
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 14 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - The Cross in the Land of the Khukuri - 15 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Posters, including of Bhutan, large calendar, no date (Box OV1)
    - Evangelical Presbyterian Church, Sikkim, Millennium Celebration Souvenir, 2000 (Box OV1)
  - Unclassified Material - General Non-Christian
    - Britain-Nepal Society Journal, 1978-1982 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Contains four publications of the journal: No. 2 - 1978 No. 3 - 1979 No. 4 - 1980 No. 6 - 1982
    - Himal Magazine - 1, 1995-1998 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Contains 12 issues of the magazine: January/February 1995, March/April 1995, May/June 1995, Sept/Oct 1995, March 1996, January 1998, February 1998, March 1998, April 1998, May 1998, June 1998, July 1998
    - Himal Magazine - 2, 1993-1994 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      This folder contains issues with the following dates: Jul/Aug 1993, 2 copies of Sept/Oct 1993, Nov/Dec 1993, Jan/Feb 1994, Mar/Apr 1994, May/Jun 1994, Jul/Aug 1994, Sep/Oct 1994
    - Himal Magazine - 3, 1991-1993 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      This folder contains 12 issues of Himal Magazine for the dates: May/June 1991, July/August 1991, September/October 1991, January/February 1992, March/April 1992, May/June 1992, July/August 1992, September/October 1992, November/December 1992, January/February 1993, March/April 1993, May/June 1993
    - HImal Magazine - 4, 1988-1991 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      This folder contains 12 issues of the magazine with the following dates: November/December 1988, January/February 1989, March/April 1989, July/August 1989, September/October 1989, November/December 1989, January/February 1990, May/June 1990 (2 copies), September/October 1990, November/December 1990, March/April 1991
    - Himalaya Magazine - 1, 1989-1991 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      This folder contains five issues of the magazine Himalaya, An Indian Quarterly. The issues have the following dates: March-May 1989, June-August 1989, September-November 1989, March-August 1991, September-November 1991.
    - Himalaya Magazine - 2, 1991-1994 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      This folder contains five issues of Himalaya Magazine including the following dates: December 1991-May 1992, June-August 1992, September 1992-February 1993, March-August 1993, January-March 1994.
    - The Independent Newspaper, 1994 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      This folder contains seven issues of the newspaper for the following dates: JUly 13-19, 1994; August 17-23, 1994; August 24-30, 1994; August 31-September 6, 1994; September 7-13, 1994; September 14-20, 1994; September 21-27, 1994.
    - Media Nepal Magazine, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      This folder contains two copies of The Monthly Magazine Media Nepal dated January, 1990.
    - Miscellaneous Research Magazines, 1985-1991 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      Titles: People of Nepal: A Research and DIgestive Quarterly Journal of Nepal Sociology (October, 1991); Research Paper Series: Wages and Welfare: The Case of Attached vs. Casual Labor in the Nepal Tarai by Bhimendra B. Katwal (July, 1986); Himalayan Research Bulletin (Monsoon/Fall, 1985)
    - Miscellaneous Articles and Material, 1950-2006 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      This folder contains many articles printed from the website nepalnews.com. It also includes an article from the Journal of the Royal Horticultural Society entited "Plant Collecting in Nepal." The final item in the folder is a small orange banner with Bible verses on it from the Winter Gospel Trekking in 1998 as part of the Sikkim Ad 2000 & Beyond movement.